<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed/steps.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-02T10:39:16+01:00</updated><id>/feed/steps.xml</id><title type="html">The van build | Steps</title><subtitle>The site for the bridgeborbarnvsky vanbuild</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Electrics research</title><link href="/steps/electrics-research.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Electrics research" /><published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/steps/electrics-research</id><content type="html" xml:base="/steps/electrics-research.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Research electrics and <a href="/electrics/#dangers">realize it could kill you</a>. This involves trolling the internet for ridiculous van builds for people with way too much time and money on their hands,
asking questions <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/vandwellers/comments/ts2gd8/wiring_ordering/i2pez2u/?context=3">getting the worst answers</a>
, and drawing up a diagram. Post it on the internet and see hundreds of people shit on it. Post it again. Rinse and repeat until you’re fairly certain you won’t kill yourself and your significant other. Congrats, you’ve earned the right to buy one grand worth of kit for a fridge and phone charger. Question whether it’s worth it, but revel in the fact that you’re getting “free energy”. That’s (of course) once you learn to strip and crimp wires, size fuses properly, read every manual for every piece of equipment you were told to buy, and invariably realize you’re missing something.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Research electrics and realize it could kill you. This involves trolling the internet for ridiculous van builds for people with way too much time and money on their hands, asking questions getting the worst answers , and drawing up a diagram. Post it on the internet and see hundreds of people shit on it. Post it again. Rinse and repeat until you’re fairly certain you won’t kill yourself and your significant other. Congrats, you’ve earned the right to buy one grand worth of kit for a fridge and phone charger. Question whether it’s worth it, but revel in the fact that you’re getting “free energy”. That’s (of course) once you learn to strip and crimp wires, size fuses properly, read every manual for every piece of equipment you were told to buy, and invariably realize you’re missing something.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Floor</title><link href="/steps/floor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Floor" /><published>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/steps/floor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/steps/floor.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Use paper to try and come up with a template for your van flooring. Stick them together with some gaffer tape and, while it’s apparently snowing and blowing up a storm, attempt to take this huge fragile template into your flat across the street, up the stairs, through the flat itself, then down the spiral staircase into the garden. It’ll be fine.</li>
  <li>Take your giant 165cmx122cm piece of plywood (your floor) and try to shimmy it free from the ridiculous place you put it in. Your neighbor’s child will come in and try to assist, he’s amazing company but seven years old and more of a moral support. With the neighbour’s kid, attempt to pivot around the flat to the spiral staircase. Tell the kid to get far away and act as a lookout as it suddenly crosses your mind that if you hurt the kid the neighbor might not help anymore. Take the giant piece of wood and angle it over the top of the staircase while your partner frantically runs to the bottom of the staircase as you barely hold onto it on your own to catch it at the bottom. The kid recently learned about gravity, and encourages us to just drop it. Don’t listen to the kid.</li>
  <li>When the inevitable storm hits, run around your garden frantically and put a tarp over your wood and (precious) template. Find objects around the garden to keep the tarp down in the wind. Things lying around, like a cement bust of a sheep (for whatever reason).</li>
  <li>After the storm clears, unwrap your wood and try and draw the template that has blown around in the wind. The minute you align one side, the other comes up in the wind, and the minute you align the other side, the middle comes up (as the template is like 50 pieces of paper). Wrestle it down by having you lie on top of it while your partner quickly draws around it between gusts of wind.</li>
  <li>Lift the wood onto some surface that’ll allow you to cut through it with a jigsaw. The minute before you do so, the neighbor’s cat will go under your plywood and sort of sit there for no reason. Attempt to scare the cat off but realize that you just need to wait.</li>
  <li>Cut out the shapes you need, but realize that there’s some ambiguity in the drawing. Cut anyway, life is short.</li>
  <li>Carry the cut wood up the spiral garden staircase, through the flat, down the staircase, across the street into the van. Attempt to put it in the van but it doesn’t fit. Do some improvisational cuts until it does.</li>
  <li>Realize you’ve only done 1/3 of the van floor. Rinse and repeat step 18-24 two more absurd times.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Use paper to try and come up with a template for your van flooring. Stick them together with some gaffer tape and, while it’s apparently snowing and blowing up a storm, attempt to take this huge fragile template into your flat across the street, up the stairs, through the flat itself, then down the spiral staircase into the garden. It’ll be fine. Take your giant 165cmx122cm piece of plywood (your floor) and try to shimmy it free from the ridiculous place you put it in. Your neighbor’s child will come in and try to assist, he’s amazing company but seven years old and more of a moral support. With the neighbour’s kid, attempt to pivot around the flat to the spiral staircase. Tell the kid to get far away and act as a lookout as it suddenly crosses your mind that if you hurt the kid the neighbor might not help anymore. Take the giant piece of wood and angle it over the top of the staircase while your partner frantically runs to the bottom of the staircase as you barely hold onto it on your own to catch it at the bottom. The kid recently learned about gravity, and encourages us to just drop it. Don’t listen to the kid. When the inevitable storm hits, run around your garden frantically and put a tarp over your wood and (precious) template. Find objects around the garden to keep the tarp down in the wind. Things lying around, like a cement bust of a sheep (for whatever reason). After the storm clears, unwrap your wood and try and draw the template that has blown around in the wind. The minute you align one side, the other comes up in the wind, and the minute you align the other side, the middle comes up (as the template is like 50 pieces of paper). Wrestle it down by having you lie on top of it while your partner quickly draws around it between gusts of wind. Lift the wood onto some surface that’ll allow you to cut through it with a jigsaw. The minute before you do so, the neighbor’s cat will go under your plywood and sort of sit there for no reason. Attempt to scare the cat off but realize that you just need to wait. Cut out the shapes you need, but realize that there’s some ambiguity in the drawing. Cut anyway, life is short. Carry the cut wood up the spiral garden staircase, through the flat, down the staircase, across the street into the van. Attempt to put it in the van but it doesn’t fit. Do some improvisational cuts until it does. Realize you’ve only done 1/3 of the van floor. Rinse and repeat step 18-24 two more absurd times.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Batons</title><link href="/steps/batons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Batons" /><published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/steps/batons</id><content type="html" xml:base="/steps/batons.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Measure your van for the batons. Realize that the bottom of the van is wavy for no fucking reason and you can either put your batons over or under the waves. You choose over, but you spend way too long agonising over the decision.</li>
  <li>Cut your batons, but realize that they don’t fit where you measured really. Try to sand them down, but realize that won’t work. In the street just saw pieces off until they sort of fit.</li>
  <li>Put thick insulation on the wheel arches. Marvel at the fact this was easy enough to do.</li>
  <li>Glue your batons, and use “No More Nails” adhesive. Realize that you should’ve used sikaflex and say fuck it and just go with it anyway. Notice that the batons you put in the step sort of don’t stick anymore, but conclude that step is always going to make a sound like that and you’re fine with it.</li>
  <li>Put insulation between the batons. Begin by using the think insulation, but give up quickly. Go to the shop, get the shitty stuff that’s easy to cut, and get some more insulating tape. The tape is inexplicably over £16 but you’re too tired to do anything about it at this point.</li>
  <li>Some of the batons may just come un-stuck. Wonder if you should’ve used sikaflex but whatever. Glue them back on</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Measure your van for the batons. Realize that the bottom of the van is wavy for no fucking reason and you can either put your batons over or under the waves. You choose over, but you spend way too long agonising over the decision. Cut your batons, but realize that they don’t fit where you measured really. Try to sand them down, but realize that won’t work. In the street just saw pieces off until they sort of fit. Put thick insulation on the wheel arches. Marvel at the fact this was easy enough to do. Glue your batons, and use “No More Nails” adhesive. Realize that you should’ve used sikaflex and say fuck it and just go with it anyway. Notice that the batons you put in the step sort of don’t stick anymore, but conclude that step is always going to make a sound like that and you’re fine with it. Put insulation between the batons. Begin by using the think insulation, but give up quickly. Go to the shop, get the shitty stuff that’s easy to cut, and get some more insulating tape. The tape is inexplicably over £16 but you’re too tired to do anything about it at this point. Some of the batons may just come un-stuck. Wonder if you should’ve used sikaflex but whatever. Glue them back on]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Panels and bulkhead</title><link href="/steps/panels-and-bulkhead.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Panels and bulkhead" /><published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/steps/panels-and-bulkhead</id><content type="html" xml:base="/steps/panels-and-bulkhead.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Put the solar panel on the roof. Screw into your van, and when it rains watch as the water goes through those holes your just screwed. Realize that you probably should’ve glued it with sikaflex, so you glue it with sikaflex - on top of the holes. This just makes the leaking problem permanent. Wait until your neighbor takes an interest and puts a nut + bolt on it saving the day.</li>
  <li>Clean the van. You probably should’ve done this sooner.</li>
  <li>Take the bulkhead out. Many of the screws are easy enough to take out, but some of them prove to be incredibly stubborn. Give up and hope your neighbor takes an interest as he knows much more than you about this stuff. Start to realize this neighbor has saved the day too many times but struggle figuring out how to repay him.</li>
  <li>Fill all cavities with as much insulation as you can, the wooly stuff. Wonder if it’s enough, but never really know.</li>
  <li>Put sound deadening on. Wonder what they’re for and realize you’ll never really know.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Put the solar panel on the roof. Screw into your van, and when it rains watch as the water goes through those holes your just screwed. Realize that you probably should’ve glued it with sikaflex, so you glue it with sikaflex - on top of the holes. This just makes the leaking problem permanent. Wait until your neighbor takes an interest and puts a nut + bolt on it saving the day. Clean the van. You probably should’ve done this sooner. Take the bulkhead out. Many of the screws are easy enough to take out, but some of them prove to be incredibly stubborn. Give up and hope your neighbor takes an interest as he knows much more than you about this stuff. Start to realize this neighbor has saved the day too many times but struggle figuring out how to repay him. Fill all cavities with as much insulation as you can, the wooly stuff. Wonder if it’s enough, but never really know. Put sound deadening on. Wonder what they’re for and realize you’ll never really know.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preparing the van</title><link href="/steps/preparing-the-van.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preparing the van" /><published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/steps/preparing-the-van</id><content type="html" xml:base="/steps/preparing-the-van.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Find cheap van. Wait like four months for a good deal.</li>
  <li>Get a parking permit, insurance, MOT, Tax etc. and regret buying a vehicle</li>
  <li>Get a mechanic to look at it. Preferably if you don’t understand what they’re saying.</li>
  <li>Rip out all the wood paneling on the van and realize that you probably should’ve kept it to make a template out of. Conclude it’s fine, how difficult could it be?</li>
  <li>Take out all the screws and other bits of metal in the van and realize you now have a bunch of holes in your van to the outside. Panic, and find some way to fill them.</li>
  <li>Strip off any rusty bits with steel wool and paint over them. Preferably in a barn.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Find cheap van. Wait like four months for a good deal. Get a parking permit, insurance, MOT, Tax etc. and regret buying a vehicle Get a mechanic to look at it. Preferably if you don’t understand what they’re saying. Rip out all the wood paneling on the van and realize that you probably should’ve kept it to make a template out of. Conclude it’s fine, how difficult could it be? Take out all the screws and other bits of metal in the van and realize you now have a bunch of holes in your van to the outside. Panic, and find some way to fill them. Strip off any rusty bits with steel wool and paint over them. Preferably in a barn.]]></summary></entry></feed>